Finding Aid for Arthur H. Vandenberg Papers, 1884-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arthur H. Vandenberg papers
1884-1974
1915-1951
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Republican U.S. Senator from Michigan; advocate of the United Nations and bipartisan foreign policy. Correspondence, scrapbooks, diaries, and visual materials.
86746 Aa/2 AA
8 linear feet on 11 microfilm rolls
25 volumes
20 phonograph records
1 film reels
1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
In 1963, Arthur H. Vandenberg Jr. donated the papers of his father to the William Clements Library of the University of Michigan. In 1974, with the permission of the family, the papers were transferred to the Bentley Historical Library. Donor no. 5425
Although the collection is open to research without restriction, researchers (except with special permission) must use the microfilm of those portions of the collection that have been filmed.
This finding aid describes those portions of the Vandenberg papers that have been microfilmed as well as that material, such as photographs and sound recordings, that has not been microfilmed. The microfilm can be borrowed through Interlibrary Loan.
Arthur Hendrick Vandenberg was born in Grand Rapids, Michigan, on March 22, 1884, to Aaron and Alpha (Hendrick) Vandenberg. He graduated from Grand Rapids High School in 1900 and studied for a year at the University of Michigan (1900-1901). Although he received numerous honorary law and other degrees later in life, this marked the end of his formal education.
Vandenberg first started out to be a journalist and author. He dropped out of college in 1901 to work full-time at the Grand Rapids Herald, where as a young man he had worked as a copy boy. For a short time he worked at Collier's Weekly magazine in New York, but returned home in 1905 to marry Elizabeth Watson. In 1906, he went back to the Herald, becoming its editor, and after 1919, its financial manager as well. During this period, Vandenberg wrote three books: The Greatest American: Alexander Hamilton (1921), If Hamilton Were Here Today (1923), and The Trail of a Tradition (1926). He remained at the Herald until 1928 when he left for Washington and the U.S. Senate.
In this first phase of his career, Vandenberg was both a newspaperman and a local political figure. He was a member of the Grand Rapids Charter Commission in 1910, a member of the Republican State Central Committee from 1912 to 1918, and chairman of the Republican State Convention in 1916 and 1928 In addition, the editorials he wrote, especially those relating to problems of local government, brought Vandenberg to the public's attention and he became a noteworthy figure in the state Republican party.
In 1928, Vandenberg was appointed to fill a Republican vacancy on the U.S. Senate. He was elected in his own right that same year and then re-elected in 1934, 1940, and 1946. When he died in 1951, he was still in office. During the 72nd Congress Vandenberg was chairman of the Committee on Enrolled Bills, during the 79th he was chairman of the Republican Conference, and during the 80th he was President pro tempore of the Senate and chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee. Three times his name came up as a possibility for President of the United States, in 1936, 1940 and again in 1948, although he was never nominated to run.
Although he had been a staunch isolationist, having opposed U.S. participation in the League of Nations during the 1930s, Vandenberg gradually converted his thinking to internationalism. In a speech he made to the Senate in January 1945, he committed himself to the idea of one world, stating that no nation could exist safely on its own and emphasizing that the United States had to be a leader in world affairs. After that speech, President Roosevelt named him a delegate to the charter conference for the United Nations, convened in San Francisco in 1945. Vandenberg also became a delegate to the first and second United Nations General Assemblies in London and New York in 1946. In 1947, he was a delegate to the Pan American Conference in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. He was actively involved in getting bipartisan support for U.S. ratification of the U.N. Charter in 1945; in winning the Senate's approval of the Truman Doctrine and the Marshall Plan; and in forming the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, authoring the Vandenberg Resolution which was approved by the Senate in 1948.
In 1906 Vandenberg married Elizabeth Watson, whom he had known for much of his life. Their three children were Arthur Jr., Barbara, and Elizabeth. She died in 1916 and Vandenberg married Hazel Whitaker in 1918. The second Mrs. Vandenberg died in 1950. The senator died of cancer on April 18, 1951, and was buried in Oak Hill Cemetery in Grand Rapids, his lifelong home.
The Arthur H. Vandenberg collection consists of 8 linear feet of materials (available on microfilm), 25 volumes of scrapbook/journals, and assorted audio and visual materials. The collection covers Vandenberg's entire career with a few folders of papers post-dating his death in 1951 relating to the dedication of memorial rooms in his honor in the 1970s. The collection is divided into seven series:
Correspondence -- Rolls 1-5
Speeches -- Rolls 6-8
Campaign and Miscellaneous Topical -- Roll 8
Clippings, Articles, and Scrapbooks Clippings, Articles -- Rolls 8-9 Scrapbook -- not filmed
Miscellaneous and Personal -- Rolls 9-11
Visual Materials Photographs, cartoons -- Roll 11, (originals in Boxes 7 and 9) Motion pictures -- Box 8
Sound Recordings
The Arthur H. Vandenberg collection consists of 8 linear feet of materials (available on microfilm), 25 volumes of scrapbook/journals, and assorted audio and visual materials. The collection covers Vandenberg's entire career with a few folders of papers post-dating his death in 1951 relating to the dedication of memorial rooms in his honor in the 1970s. The collection is divided into four major series: Correspondence; Speeches; Campaign and Miscellaneous Topical; Clippings, Articles, and Scrapbooks; Miscellaneous and Personal; Visual Materials; and Sound Recordings.
Subjects:
African Americans.; America First Committee.; Nuclear energy.; Banks and banking--United States.; Children--Employment.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; Communism.; Detroit (Mich.) Citizens League.; Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.; Florida Ship Canal (Projected); Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Isle Royale (Mich.); Israel.; Jews--Michigan.; Labor movement.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.; Neutrality.; Polish Americans--Michigan.; Presidents--United States--Election--1940.; Presidents--United States--Election--1944.; Presidents--United States--Election--1948.; Republican Party (Mich.); Saint Lawrence Seaway.; Tariff--United States.; Taxation--United States.; United Nations.; United States. Congress. Senate.; United States--Politics and government--1901-1953.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Cigars.; Clothing and dress.; Festivals.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Interiors.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959.; Military parades and ceremonies.; Offices.; Politics and government--1939-1945.; Politics and government--1946-1960.; Public speaking.; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953.; Telephones--1911-1920.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; United Nations.; United States. Congress. Senate.; Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1907-1968.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Vandenberg, Hazel Whittaker, 1882-1950.; Vandenberg family.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Women.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
Contributors:
Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.; Aiken, George D. (George David), 1892-1984.; American Profit Sharing Institute.; Americans for Democratic Action.; Andrews, Roger, 1874-; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Annenberg, Walter H., 1908-2002; Armour, Norman.; Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1893-1973; Austin, Warren Robinson, 1877-1963.; Averill, George R., 1893-1971.; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.; Baldwin, Raymond E. (Raymond Earl), 1893-1986; Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965.; Bender, George Harrison, 1896-1961.; Bennett, John B. (John Bonifas), 1905-1964.; Benton, William, 1900-1973.; Beukema, John C., 1888-1967.; Blodgett, John Wood, 1860-1951.; Bohlen, Charles E. (Charles Eustis), 1904-1974; Bolton, Chester Castle, 1882-1939.; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940.; Bradley, Frederick Van Ness, 1898-1947.; Brake, D. Hale, 1891-1979; Bridges, Styles, 1898-1961.; Brownell, Herbert, 1904-1996; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Butler, Hugh Alfred, 1878-1954.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.; Byrnes, James Francis, 1879-1972.; Cain, Harry P. (Harry Pulliam), 1906-1979; Cannon, Joseph Gurney, 1836-1926.; Capehart, Homer E. (Homer Earl), 1897-1979.; Capper, Arthur, 1865-1951.; Case, Francis H. (Francis Higbee), 1896-1962.; Chennault, Claire Lee, 1890-1958.; Clayton, Will, 1880-1966.; Connally, Tom, 1877-1963.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Cooper, John Sherman, 1901-1991; Copeland, Royal S. (Royal Samuel), 1868-1938.; Couzens, Frank, 1902-1950.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Craig, Charles Patton, 1858-1935.; Crowley, Leo T.; Cudlip, William Byrnes, 1904-; Cummins, Albert Baird, 1850-1926.; Curtis, Charles, 1860-1936.; Dawes, Charles Gates, 1865-1951.; Denby, Edwin, 1870-1929.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Donnell, Forrest C., 1884-1980; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Duff, James H. (James Henderson), 1883-1969.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.; Eccles, Marriner S. (Marriner Stoddard), 1890-1977.; Edwards, George, 1914-; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Fairbanks, Charles W. (Charles Warren), 1852-1918.; Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.; Flanders, Ralph E. (Ralph Edward), 1880-1970.; Fletcher, Mr. (Duncan Upshaw), 1859-1936.; Forrestal, James, 1892-1949.; Gannett, Frank E. (Frank Ernest), 1876-1957.; Green, Dwight H., 1897-1958.; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Green, William, 1870-1952.; Grew, Joseph C. (Joseph Clark), 1880-1965.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.; Hazlitt, Henry, 1894-1993; Herring, Clyde L. (Clyde LaVerne), 1879-1945.; Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966.; Hickenlooper, Bourke B. (Bourke Blakemore), 1896-1971.; Hiss, Alger.; Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Howard, Roy Wilson, 1883-1964.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.; Hurley, Patrick J. (Patrick Jay), 1883-1963.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952.; Jeffries, Edward, 1900-1950; Johnson, Hiram, 1866-1945.; Judd, Dorothy.; Kendall, David Walbridge, 1903-1976.; Kersten, Charles J., 1902-; Kettle, Earl.; Knowland, William F. (William Fife), 1908-1974; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; Krock, Arthur, 1886-1974; Lamont, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1870-1948.; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987.; Langer, William, 1886-1959.; Lasker, Albert Davis, 1880-1952.; Lawrence, David, 1888-; Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1902-1985; Lovett, Robert A. (Robert Abercrombie), 1895-1986; Lucas, Scott Wike, 1892-1968; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967.; McAdoo, William Gibbs, 1863-1941.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.; Machrowicz, Thaddeus Michael, 1899-1970; Maddy, Joseph E. (Joseph Edgar), 1891-1966.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959.; Mellon, Andrew W. (Andrew William), 1855-1939.; Menefee, Ferdinand Northrup, 1886-; Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; Millikin, Eugene Donald, 1891-1958.; Mooney, Edward, Archbishop, 1882-1958; Morse, Wayne L. (Wayne Lyman), 1900-1974.; Moses, George Higgins, 1869-1944.; Mott, Charles S., 1875-1973.; Mundt, Karl E. (Karl Earl), 1900-1974; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Murrow, Edward R.; Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.; Norbeck, Peter, 1870-1936.; O'Conor, Herbert R. (Herbert Romulus), 1896-1960.; Page, Herman, 1866-1942.; Patterson, Robert Porter, 1891-1952.; Perry, Stuart Hoffman, 1874-1957.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968; Reed, Clyde Martin, 1871-1949.; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970.; Riggs, Henry Earle, 1865-1949.; Riley, James Whitcomb, 1849-1916.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979; Scholle, August, 1904-; Schwellenbach, Lewis Baxter, 1894-1948.; Scott, Hugh, 1900-1994; Sloan, Alfred P. (Alfred Pritchard), 1875-1966.; Smith, George Otis, 1871-1944.; Smith, Gerald L. K. (Gerald Lyman Kenneth), 1898-1976; Snyder, John W. (John Wesley), 1895-1985.; Stassen, Harold E. (Harold Edward), 1907-2001; Stettinius, Edward R. (Edward Reilly), 1900-1949.; Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.; Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952.; Sweet, Edwin F. (Edwin Forrest), 1847-1935.; Taft, Charles P. (Charles Phelps), 1897-1983; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Thomas, R. J. (Rolland Jay), 1900-1967; Thompson, Dorothy, 1894-1961.; Thorp, Willard Long, 1899-1992; Titus, Harold, 1888-1967.; Toy, Harry Stanley, 1892-1955.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tufty, Esther Van Wagoner, d. 1986.; Vinson, Fred M., 1890-1953.; Waite, John Barker, 1882-1967; Wallace, William Henry, 1861-1933.; Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.; Weeks, Sinclair, 1892-; Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961.; Welsh, George Wilson, 1883-1974.; Wherry, Kenneth Spicer, 1892-1951.; White, Wallace Humphrey, 1877-1952.; White, Walter Francis, 1893-1955.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Winslow, Rollin.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.; Wood, Robert E.; Woodfill, W. Stewart, b. 1896.; Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953.; Ziegler, Charles M., 1888-1959.
Sound Recordings
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.
Genre/Form:
Albums.; Caricatures.; Cartoons.; Diaries.; Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Correspondence, 1915-1951; 3 linear feet
  Correspondence (3 linear feet) is arranged chronologically (except for a scattering of special topic files) and covers the years 1915-1951. Correspondents include the major political and public figures of the day, including Dean Acheson, Thomas Dewey, John Foster Dulles, Herbert Hoover, Henry Cabot Lodge, Franklin D. Roosevelt, and Harry S. Truman. Researchers should note that the correspondence is but a fragment of what once existed. The files were severely weeded prior to their coming to the University of Michigan.
  - By date
    - 1915-1918 (Reel 1)
    - 1919-1920 (Reel 1)
    - 1921-1922 (Reel 1)
    - 1923-1924 (Reel 1)
    - 1925 (Reel 1)
    - 1926-1927 (Reel 1)
    - 1928-1929 (Reel 1)
    - 1930 (Reel 1)
    - 1931 (Reel 1)
    - January-September 1932 (Reel 1)
    - October-November 1932 (Reel 1)
    - December 1932 (Reel 1)
    - 1933 (Reel 1)
    - January-February 1934 (Reel 1)
    - March 1934 (Reel 1)
    - April 1934 (Reel 1)
    - May-December 1934 (Reel 1)
    - 1935 (Reel 1)
    - January-February 1936 (Reel 2)
    - March 1936 (Reel 2)
    - April 1936 (Reel 2)
    - May-November 1936 (Reel 2)
    - December 1936 (Reel 2)
    - January-February 1937 (Reel 2)
    - March-April 1937 (Reel 2)
    - May-July 1937 (Reel 2)
    - August-December 1937 (Reel 2)
    - January-February 1938 (Reel 2)
    - March-May 1938 (Reel 2)
    - June 1938 (Reel 2)
    - July-August 1938 (Reel 2)
    - September 1938 (Reel 2)
    - October 1938 (Reel 2)
    - November 1-15, 1938 (Reel 2)
    - November 16-30, 1938 (Reel 2)
    - December 1938 (Reel 2)
    - January-February 1939 (Reel 2)
    - March-April 1939 (Reel 2)
    - May 1-8, 1939 (Reel 2)
    - May 9-31, 1939 (Reel 2)
    - June-September 1939 (Reel 2)
    - October 1939 (Reel 2)
    - November 1939 (Reel 2)
    - December 1939 (Reel 2)
    - January 1940 (Reel 3)
    - February 1940 (Reel 3)
    - March-April 1940 (Reel 3)
    - May 1940 (Reel 3)
    - June-July 1940 (Reel 3)
    - August 1940 (Reel 3)
    - September 1940 (Reel 3)
    - October-December 1940 (Reel 3)
    - January 1941 (Reel 3)
    - February-March 1941 (Reel 3)
    - April-June 1941 (Reel 3)
    - July-August 1941 (Reel 3)
    - September-October 1941 (Reel 3)
    - November-December 1941 (Reel 3)
    - January-February 1942 (Reel 3)
    - March-April 1942 (Reel 3)
    - May-June 1942 (Reel 3)
    - July-December 1942 (Reel 3)
    - January-February 1943 (Reel 3)
    - March 1943 (Reel 3)
    - April-June 1943 (Reel 3)
    - July-September 1943 (Reel 3)
    - October-December 1943 (Reel 3)
    - January-February 1944 (Reel 3)
    - March 1944 (Reel 3)
    - April 1-15, 1944 (Reel 3)
    - April 16-30, 1944 (Reel 3)
    - May 1-14, 1944 (Reel 3)
    - May 15-31, 1944 (Reel 3)
    - June 1944 (Reel 3)
    - July-September 1944 (Reel 3)
    - October-November 1944 (Reel 3)
    - December 1944 (Reel 3)
    - January 1945 (Reel 3)
    - February 1945 (Reel 3)
    - March 1-15, 1945 (Reel 3)
    - March 16-31, 1945 (Reel 3)
    - April 1945 (Reel 3)
    - May-June 1945 (Reel 3)
    - July 1-20, 1945 (Reel 3)
    - July 21-31, 1945 (Reel 3)
    - August 1945 (Reel 3)
    - September 1945 (Reel 4)
    - October 1945 (Reel 4)
    - November 1945 (Reel 4)
    - December 1-15, 1945 (Reel 4)
    - December 16-31, 1945 (Reel 4)
    - January-February 1946 (Reel 4)
    - March 1946 (Reel 4)
    - April 1946 (Reel 4)
    - May 1946 (Reel 4)
    - June 1946 (Reel 4)
    - July 1946 (Reel 4)
    - August 1946 (Reel 4)
    - September 1946 (Reel 4)
    - October-November 1946 (Reel 4)
    - December 1946 (Reel 4)
    - January 1947 (Reel 4)
    - February 1947 (Reel 4)
    - March 1-10, 1947 (Reel 4)
    - March 11-20, 1947 (Reel 4)
    - March 21-31, 1947 (Reel 4)
    - April 1947 (Reel 4)
    - May 1947 (Reel 4)
    - June 1-19, 1947 (Reel 4)
    - June 20-30, 1947 (Reel 4)
    - July 1947 (Reel 4)
    - August 1947 (Reel 4)
    - September 1947 (Reel 4)
    - October 1-19, 1947 (Reel 4)
    - October 20-31, 1947 (Reel 4)
    - November-December 1947 (Reel 4)
    - January 1948 (Reel 4)
    - February 1-14, 1948 (Reel 4)
    - February 15-29, 1948 (Reel 4)
    - March 1-15, 1948 (Reel 4)
    - March 16-31, 1948 (Reel 4)
    - April 1-10, 1948 (Reel 4)
    - April 11-30, 1948 (Reel 4)
    - May 1948 (Reel 4)
    - June 1-10, 1948 (Reel 4)
    - June 11-30, 1948 (Reel 5)
    - July 1948 (Reel 5)
    - August 1948 (Reel 5)
    - September 1948 (Reel 5)
    - October-November 1948 (Reel 5)
    - December 1948 (Reel 5)
    - January 1949 (Reel 5)
    - February 1-14, 1949 (Reel 5)
    - February 15-28, 1949 (Reel 5)
    - March 1949 (Reel 5)
    - April 1949 (Reel 5)
    - May 1949 (Reel 5)
    - June 1-15, 1949 (Reel 5)
    - June 16-30, 1949 (Reel 5)
    - July 1949 (Reel 5)
    - August 1949 (Reel 5)
    - September 1949 (Reel 5)
    - October 1-15, 1949 (Reel 5)
    - October 16-31, 1949 (Reel 5)
    - November 1949 (Reel 5)
    - December 1949 (Reel 5)
    - January 1-15, 1950 (Reel 5)
    - January 16-31, 1950 (Reel 5)
    - February-May 1950 (Reel 5)
    - June 1950 (Reel 5)
    - July 1950 (Reel 5)
    - August 1950 (Reel 5)
    - September 1950 (Reel 5)
    - October 1950 (Reel 5)
    - November 1950 (Reel 5)
    - December 1950 (Reel 5)
    - January 1-15, 1951 (Reel 5)
    - January 16-31, 1951 (Reel 5)
    - February 1951 (Reel 5)
    - March-November 1951 (Reel 5)
  - Various
    - Letters from AHV (from various sources) (Reel 5)
    - Letters to family, 1891-1923 (Reel 5)
    - AHV letters to Hazel Whitaker, 1918 (Reel 5)
    - AHV letters to Hazel Whitaker, circa 1918 (Reel 5)
    - Letters of family members to AHV and HWV (Reel 5)
    - HWV letters to family members (Reel 5)
    - Letter to Mrs. Julius Amberg; and miscellanea, circa 1950-1951 (Reel 5)
- Speeches
  The Speeches (ca. 1 linear ft.) series is arranged chronologically and covers the period of 1900-1947. The speeches were given both in the U.S. Senate and to various other public and political gatherings.
  - 1900, 1918; 1920 undated
    - Grand Rapids High School Oratorical Contest, April 1900 (Reel 6)
    - "One of the Many Who Are Dying for Liberty", September 20, 1918 (Reel 6)
    - Reprinted from "Saturday Night" Charlevoix, Michigan (Reel 6)
    - University of Michigan Speech, circa 1920 (Reel 6)
  - 1925, 1927
    - "Internationalism --Good and Bad", April 16, 1925 (Reel 6)
    - "Mackinac and History"-delivered at Fort Mackinac Michigan to the Memorial Luncheon of the Governors' Conference in the United States, July 25, 1927 (Reel 6)
    - , "The Right of Industrial Petition", 1927 undated (Reel 6)
  - 1928
    - "A Program to Stimulate Prosperity in Times of Unemployment and Business Depression", April 21, 1928 (Reel 6)
    - Speech to Members of the Society of American Newspaper Editors, April 24, 1928 (Reel 6)
    - Memorial address: Senator Woodbridge N. Ferris, May 6, 1928 (Reel 6)
    - "Reapportionment", May 29, 1928 (Reel 6)
    - Michigan Republican State Convention. Detroit., September 19, 1928 (Reel 6)
  - 1929
    - "The Reapportionment Bill", January 24, 1929 (Reel 6)
    - "Proceedings for Contempt of Court", September 20, 1929 (Reel 6)
    - "Dedication of University of Michigan League", June 14, 1929 (Reel 6)
    - Grand Rapids' Rotary Club, November 8, 1928 (Reel 6)
    - "Michigan's War Dead", October 7, 1929 (Reel 6)
    - January 9, 1939 & January 14, 1930 "Michigan and the Sugar Tariff" (Reel 6)
    - "Michigan and the Sugar Tariff", March 5, 1930 (Reel 6)
    - "Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Waterway" Detroit. [Speech by Henry J. Allen placed in CR by AHV], March 22, 1930 (Reel 6)
    - "Memorial Address" Detroit. [Burial of 86 "Polar Bears" from A.E.F. in Russia], May 30, 1930 (Reel 6)
  - 1931
    - Methodist Conference, September 8, 1931 (Reel 6)
  - 1932
    - Address concerning Christianity and Constitutionalism, circa 1932 (Reel 6)
    - Senate speech relative to the Economy, March 22, 1932 (Reel 6)
    - Address via nation-wide radio hook-up. Washington, D.C., September 21, 1932 (Reel 6)
    - January-June 1933 (Reel 6)
    - "The Banking Situation", March 23, 1933 (Reel 6)
    - "Inflation", April 26, 1933 (Reel 6)
    - "Veterans' Allowances and Adjusted Service Certificates", May 15, 1933 (Reel 6)
    - "The St. Lawrence Deep-Waterway Project", May 29, 1933 (Reel 6)
    - "Justice for Veterans", May 31, 1933 (Reel 6)
    - "Address to the National Advertising Convention" Grand Rapids, June 26, 1933 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Michigan Bankers' Association. Detroit., June 30, 1933 (Reel 6)
  - July-December 1933
    - "A Defense of the Bank Deposit Insurance Law and an Answer to the American Bankers Association" Chicago., September 12, 1933 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Gridiron Club., December 9, 1933 (Reel 6)
  - 1934
    - "Recognition of Russia", January 11, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - "Bank-Deposit Insurance", January 17, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - February 1, 2 "The Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Seaway Treaty--The Facts", 1934 (Reel 6)
    - "Republican Responsibilities for 1934" Lincoln Birthday speech delivered in Grand Rapids, February 19, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - "Take the Profit Out of War", April 12, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - "Revision of Immigration and Deportation Laws", May 14, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - "No Tariff Dictatorship", May 18, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - "Bank-Deposit Insurance the Steel Beam of Recovery, June 9, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Rockford College Graduating Class, June 12, 1934 (Reel 6)
    - "80th Anniversary-Birth of the Republican Party" Jackson, Michigan, July 7, 1934 (Reel 6)